MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不動產）
These are the landlords with whom we have a sublease contract, aren't they?
這些都是 跟我們簽了轉租合約的房東吧？
MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不動產）
None of these landlords are profitable to us.
我們從他們那裡根本賺不到錢
SUBLEASE CONTRACT
（轉租合約）
I want you to reduce their rents down to the bare bones.
我要你們把他們房產的租金降到最低
Reduce their rent?
降租？
I don't think they'll take too kindly to that.
恐怕他們不會輕易接受
If they kick up too much of a fuss,
如果他們抱怨
make them break their side of the contract
就設法讓他們違約
and make them pay the penalty.
然後讓他們支付違約金
A penalty?
違約金？
We, of course, are free to withdraw from the contract,
當然，我們可以自由地解約
but it's designed to incur huge penalties if the owners wish to do so.
但是根據合約 房東若想解約則需支付鉅額違約金
That's the goal.
這就是我們的目的
Isn't that right, sir?
對吧，社長？
Exactly.
沒錯
And now it's time.
現在時機已到
It's endgame for this town.
對本市的爭奪戰已進入尾聲
And when this town is ours, then we move on to Tachikawa.
一旦徹底掌握這裡 我們就要進軍立川市
TACHIKAWA STORE IMAGE FOR ILLUSTRATIVE PURPOSES
（立川店，概念圖）
Whoever comes out on top here will become the new manager.
誰能當上這裡的業務冠軍 就能成為那邊的新店長
Leave everything to me.
請放心交給我
LANDLORD - PROPERTY PROPERTY TYPE - RENTAL AMOUNT
（房東、房產、類型、租金）
TOSAKA REAL ESTATE
-早安
Fujiwara's landlord friends have advised us that Minerva is ripping them off.
藤原的房東朋友們說 密涅瓦不動產坑了他們
-Ripping them off? -Yeah.
-“坑”他們？ -對
They're in sublease contracts with Minerva Real Estate.
他們跟密涅瓦不動產簽了轉租合約
SUBLEASE CONTRACT (AKA SUBLET)
（轉租合約又稱分租）
The terms are stifling and they want to cancel,
條款非常苛刻，他們想取消合約
but they're demanding a huge penalty.
但密涅瓦要求他們支付鉅額違約金
Let's break it down.
我來解釋一下
MR. OKAWA'S REAL ESTATE CLASS
（大河部長的不動產講座）
Under a sublease contract,
簽訂轉租合約後
a property owner can entrust their property to an agency
房東可將房產委託給仲介機構
in exchange for a guaranteed monthly rental income.
換取有保障的月租收入
The advantages?
好處有哪些？
Not only will the agency find all of the tenants,
仲介將負責為所有空屋尋找房客
but a monthly rental income is guaranteed, even if the property is vacant,
即便有空屋閒置 房東每月仍有租金保障
thus reducing the risks to the owner.
因此能為房東降低風險
But there are also disadvantages.
但是也有一些缺點
Under a sublease contract,
簽訂轉租合約後
the relationship between owner and agency is one of lessor and lessee.
房東和仲介 就是出租人和承租人的關係
As such, the Act on Land and Building Leases applies.
《土地及建築物租賃法》 將適用於此情況
The agency is largely protected as a tenant under this Act.
根據該法案，仲介身為承租人 在很大程度上將受到保護
The agency, as the tenant,
身為承租人的仲介
can demand a rent reduction midway through the contract,
可在合約適用期內要求減租
and some contracts do not allow an owner to escape without paying a hefty fee.
也有一些合約 要求房東支付鉅額違約金以脫身
MONEY PROBLEMS
（金錢問題）
That's right.
就是這樣
SUBLEASE CONTRACT
（轉租合約）
Mrs. Matsui.
松井女士
Can you tell me exactly what Minerva told you?
能不能告訴我 密涅瓦具體跟你說了什麼？
Well, Miss Tsukishita, let me tell you.
月下小姐，是這樣的
My son said--
我兒子說…
Mom.
媽
-What are you doing? Hang up! -Wait--
-妳在幹什麼？快掛電話 -等等
-Hang up! -Mrs. Matsui. Hello?
-快掛電話 -松井女士，喂？
What is it?
怎麼了？
You remember Mrs. Matsui, right?
你還記得松井女士吧？
She's the wife of the mayor who died five years ago.
她先生曾是鎮長，五年前去世了
I remember.
我記得
She called to ask me something about Minerva,
她剛打來問我密涅瓦不動產的事
but just now her son made her hang up on me.
但她兒子逼她掛電話
They're really at it again?
難道他們又開始了嗎？
THIS MONTH'S SLOGAN: DEALS OVER FLOWERS
（本月口號：交易勝過鮮花）
Mornin'.
早安
What?
什麼？
What's with the suit and shoes?
這身行頭是什麼情況？
You noticed? They're new.
不錯吧？都是我新買的
I thought you didn't care for that?
你不是不在意這些事嗎？
I've been playing around with trading in crypto,
我最近在玩加密貨幣
and I'm making an absolute killing.
真是賺翻了
CRYPTOCURRENCY - A TYPE OF VIRTUAL CURRENCY USED
（加密貨幣是一種虛擬貨幣）
IN PLACE OF REAL PAPER MONEY
（用於代替真正的紙幣）
Check out the watch. One mil.
你們看，這支錶要一百萬
Sorry, could you please wait?
抱歉，請稍等
Sir.
先生
Kamiki.
神木
This takes me back.
好懷念
Everything's the same as always.
一切如故
You. What are you doing here?
喂，你來做什麼？
I'm here to do some scouting.
我是來挖角的
Scouting?
挖角？
Minerva will soon be opening a new branch in Tachikawa.
密涅瓦不動產很快就會 在立川開設新店
I will be its manager.
我將成為那裡的店長
I figured some of you might like to join me over there.
我想你們可能有人 會想要跟我一起過去
Of course we don't!
絕對不可能
Are you sure?
是嗎？
Tosaka Real Estate is headed down the drain.
登坂不動產就快完蛋了
Isn't this just another questionable venture in exploiting legal loopholes?
這恐怕又是一次鑽法律漏洞 不可靠的投機活動吧？
Wouldn't you like to know?
究竟是不是呢？
Cut the innocent crap!
少給我裝傻
Kamiki. It's been a while.
神木，好久不見了
Mr. Tosaka.
登坂社長
You look well.
你的氣色不錯
Why did you come back to real estate?
為何又回到了不動產行業？
To come in first.
為了當第一
You're still on about that.
這口號還是沒變啊
I will continue to be number one in the real estate industry.
我會成為不動產的業界第一
Because I promised.
因為我發過誓
A promise?
發誓？
EP 9 OF 10 A MAN NAMED KAMIKI
第9集：神木其人
HIDAMARI SO
（向陽莊）
Wow, that's delicious.
真好吃
What are these pickles?
這是什麼醃菜？
They're homemade.
是我自己做的
Lotus root and daikon, pickled overnight. Do you like them?
蓮藕和蘿蔔醃漬一晚，妳喜歡嗎？
COOKING - SAICHI
-很好吃 -太好了
You'll have to give me the recipe.
你一定得教教我配方
Of course.
當然沒問題
And also, is coming in first really such a big deal?
話說，當第一真那麼重要嗎？
What?
什麼？
I'm talking about Kamiki.
我是說神木
Right.
他啊
There was that one time when Kamiki had traveled to Macau
他有一次去了澳門
and I managed to overtake him and come in first.
我成功超越他，拿下了那個月的冠軍
He submitted his letter of resignation the following day.
結果那傢伙第二天就遞交了辭呈
LETTER OF RESIGNATION NOVEMBER 30, 2018
（辭呈，2018年11月30日）
RYOMA KAMIKI TOSAKA REAL ESTATE
（神木涼真，登坂不動產）
Why?
理由呢？
Because I did not come in first.
因為我沒拿到第一
90% COMPARED TO LAST YEAR 96 CONTRACTS
（去年的90%，96筆合約）
He quit?
他辭職了？
Just because he lost first place that one time?
就因為一次沒拿到第一？
It must have meant everything to him.
那對他來說一定非常重要
I hope you don't feel that way.
希望永瀨你沒有那種想法
What?
什麼？
There are more important things than coming in first.
比起當第一，還有很多更重要的事
Is this it?
終於可以了嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
I got the wrong idea?
我誤會了嗎？
SUBLEASE CONTRACT
（轉租合約）
What do you mean?
你們這是什麼意思？
I'm saying we're requesting to reduce the rent on all of your properties
意思是，我們要求你的所有房產減租
from the current 95,000 yen to 90,000 yen.
從目前的每月九萬五千降到九萬
You said this was a safe investment because I'd have a guaranteed income.
你們當初明明說這是安全的投資 因為我能獲得有保障的收入
NAOTO YAMADA REAL ESTATE INVESTOR &amp; EMPLOYEE
（山田直人，房產投資人，職員）
Market prices have fallen in the area.
那個地區的市價在下滑
I'm already paying you 30% of the rent in administrative fees.
我已經付了三成的租金給你們 作為管理費
But I looked into it, and it looks like you're only meant to be charging 10-20%.
但我查過 你們好像應該只收取一到兩成
You're already ripping me off, and now you want me to go down to 90,000?
你們已經坑了我一筆 現在還想讓我減租到九萬？
All I'd end up with is 63,000 yen.
那我每月只能收入六萬三千
That's not even enough to break even!
連繳房貸都不夠
I am truly sorry.
我深表歉意
I want out.
我要退出
I can't trust you guys.
我無法再信任你們
Article 28 of the Act on Land and Building Leases
《土地及建築物租賃法》第28條規定
requires justifiable grounds for a lessor to terminate their contract.
出租人解除合約需提供正當理由
A REQUIRED CRITERIA
（必要條件）
FOR APPLYING TO TERMINATE A CONTRACT
（以解除合約）
An owner feeling inconvenienced
房東單方面感到不便
is not grounds for termination.
無法構成解約的理由
What?
什麼？
If you still truly wish to terminate,
如果你鐵了心要解除合約
you'll have to pay a hefty penalty.
就必須支付鉅額違約金
The penalty would be 18 months' rent on all of your properties, which would be
也就是你所有房產18個月的租金
in the area of 20 million yen.
也就是兩千萬元左右
I won't stand for this!
我不接受
I'll see you in court!
法庭上見
Be my guest.
請便
However, you should realize
不過，你該知道
that the Supreme Court has already made rulings on this.
針對類似情況 最高法院在此之前已經有過判例
Sublessees are protected under the Act on Land and Building Leases.
承租人受到 《土地及建築物租賃法》的保護
What?
什麼？
No, no. Wait…
不，等等
What do you mean?
你這是什麼意思？
Mrs. Matsui.
松井女士
MATSUI
我想盡力幫助妳
You're a very important client of mine.
妳對我來說是非常重要的客戶
If you're in trouble, you can tell me anything.
如果妳遇到了麻煩 無論什麼事都可以告訴我
EMI MATSUI WIFE OF THE FORMER MAYOR
（松井惠美，前任鎮長之妻）
Thank you, Miss Tsukishita.
謝謝妳，月下小姐
But my son doesn't want us to ask for any help.
但我兒子不希望我們求助於任何人
Has Minerva said something to him?
是不是密涅瓦不動產跟他說了什麼？
I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉
Mrs. Matsui? Mrs. Matsui!
松井女士…
Ms. Hanasawa?
花澤？
What did you say to Mrs. Matsui's son?
妳跟松井女士的兒子說了什麼？
I didn't say anything.
我什麼也沒說
It was Kamiki.
是神木
What?
什麼？
Tsukishita.
月下
Can you help me?
妳能幫我嗎？
Kamiki's weakness?
神木的弱點？
Yes. Can you think of anything?
對，你能想到什麼嗎？
Why are you asking?
妳問這個做什麼？
I mean,
這…
isn't it just standard practice to aim for your opponent's weak spot?
這不是標準做法嗎？ “瞄準對手的弱點”
That's what Oda Nobunaga said.
這是織田信長的名言
-Did he? -Wait.
-是嗎？ -等等
Was it Hideyoshi?
是不是豐臣秀吉說的？
Ieyasu?
還是德川家康？
Napoleon?
拿破崙？
But don't you hate it when people act unfairly?
月下小姐不是很討厭 人們使用不正當手段嗎？
What?
什麼？
No, this is different.
不，這不一樣
I don't know if I'd call it a weakness,
我不知道這是不是弱點
but I know what he loves more than three square meals a day.
但我知道比起一日三餐 那傢伙更愛什麼
What is it?
是什麼？
-Money, right? -Wrong.
-是錢吧？ -錯
-Alcohol?
-喝酒？
Sweets? Tasty treats?
甜品？美味小吃？
Couldn't be more wrong.
大錯特錯
The correct answer is
正確答案是
making bets.
賭博
-Making bets? -Yep.
-賭博？ -對
Well, that's vague.
這也太籠統了
But, Mr. Nagase, you said it yourself.
不過，永瀨前輩也說過
I only ever beat him once.
我只打敗過他一次
Kamiki had been away for half the month in Macau.
當時他去了澳門，有半個月不在這裡
Right. Macau.
對，澳門那次
He was going all out at the casino at the time.
他那時非常沉迷於賭場
Ms. Hanasawa, I couldn't find Mr. Kamiki's weakness,
花澤，我沒發現神木的弱點
but I did find out what he likes.
但發現了他的喜好
It seems he's often going to Macau because he likes to gamble.
他好像經常去澳門，因為他好賭
Macau?
澳門？
Kamiki, there's this hot-shot landlady called Mrs. Kamogawa.
神木先生 有個名下有熱門房產的女房東叫鴨川
She's not listening to a word I say.
她完全不肯聽我說
Can you talk to her instead?
你能跟她談談嗎？
Mrs. Kamogawa?
鴨川？
I'm pretty sure…
我記得…
SUZUKA KAMOGAWA SUBLEASE PROPERTY INFORMATION
（鴨川鈴鹿，轉租房產資訊）
…she likes to gamble, and she often travels to Macau.
…她喜歡賭博，而且經常去澳門
Got it.
我知道了
Thank you.
謝謝
This is about what that young Nishioka guy was talking to me about, right?
你們是為了 那個叫西岡的年輕人跟我說的事吧？
I have had my concerns about that property.
我也擔心過那處房產的情況
SUZUKA KAMOGAWA RESTAURATEUR &amp; PROPERTY OWNER
（鴨川鈴鹿，餐廳老闆，房東）
He said the market had dropped and there was no way around it,
他說市場上的房租都在跌 你們也無計可施
but I looked into it myself, and the market has not dropped.
但我親自查過，市價根本沒跌
What do you say to that?
你們對此作何解釋？
I'm not entirely averse to dropping my rent.
我並非完全不肯降租
But I do hate people trying to pull a fast one on me.
但我討厭別人對我耍花招
So you can go.
所以你們可以走了
Wait, please.
請留步
I'd like to take over for you from now on.
今後請讓我來負責妳的業務吧
And what would I get out of this new exchange?
這種變動對我有什麼好處？
Whatever you desire. Name it, and it shall be yours.
妳想要什麼儘管開口，我一定辦到
Name it and it's mine?
“儘管開口”、“一定辦到”？
What are you, a genie?
難道你是神燈精靈嗎？
Indeed I am.
沒錯
I will be your servant, completely indebted to you.
我將成為鴨川大人忠實的奴僕
Tell me, what do you want?
請告訴我，妳想要什麼？
Mistress.
主人
What a smarmy act.
好爛的戲碼
No one would ever--
沒人會…
I could get used to this.
這倒真是不錯
She fell for it?
她接受了？
Is a stroke of the ego all it takes to sway a high-flying lady mogul?
只需拍拍馬屁，就能拿下一位 事業成功的女企業家嗎？
This is bad. I have to change the subject.
這可不妙，我得把話題岔開
Mrs. Kamogawa, are you still traveling to Macau these days?
鴨川女士，最近還經常去澳門嗎？
I'm not. I've just been far too busy these days.
沒有，最近忙得要死
You like to go to Macau?
妳喜歡去澳門嗎？
Yes, I go multiple times a year.
對，我一年會去好幾次
I just love going to the casino.
我超喜歡那裡的賭場
I love it there too.
我也一樣
Nothing beats the unique tension there.
那裡的緊張感獨一無二
Yes, it's simply the best.
沒錯，無與倫比
So you're both casino fans.
原來兩位都是賭場愛好者
I wonder who the luckier one is?
不知道誰的運氣比較好呢？
I tell you what, I've never once lost a bet.
這麼說吧，我從未賭輸過
Then how about a little bet?
那麼，來小賭一局如何？
A coin toss.
拋硬幣
I'm intrigued. Carry on.
我很有興趣，來吧
Yes, just what I wanted.
很好，正合我意
If I win,
若我贏了
you'll hand this property over to me.
妳就把這處房產交給我負責
Very well. I'll even consider dropping the rent.
沒問題，我甚至可以考慮降租
I'll give you my other properties as well.
我的其他房產也都交給你打理
But what if I win?
但如果我贏了呢？
If you win, I dedicate myself to you.
那樣的話，我將把自己的身體和靈魂
Heart, body, and soul.
都獻給鴨川大人
You'd bet your life on it?
你要把自己的命都賭上？
This is too fun!
太有意思了
Let's do it.
來吧
Mrs. Kamogawa is a sore loser.
鴨川是個非常輸不起的人
More so than anyone I've ever seen.
我見過的人裡無出其右
If she were to lose, she'd simply refuse to sign the contract out of spite.
如果賭輸，她一定會勃然大怒 拒絕在合約上簽字
This side is heads
這是正面
and this side is tails.
這是反面
I pick tails.
我選反面
Then I am heads.
那我選正面
If by some chance Kamiki wins and she doesn't get mad…
萬一神木贏了，而她沒有惱羞成怒…
KAMIKI - HEADS KAMOGAWA - TAILS
（神木，人頭，鴨川，鳥紋）
…I just have to accuse him of cheating.
…那我就說他作弊
And so there's no way
那麼，這傢伙就絕不可能
Kamiki can win this contract through this little bet.
利用這場小賭拿下合約
Which is it?
是什麼？
You see!
看吧
I won!
我贏了
Well done.
真厲害
My heart was pounding there for a second.
有那麼一瞬間，我的心都快跳出來了
That was so much fun.
太好玩了
Then we're done. You can go now.
那麼結束了，你們走吧
You won, and so I shall keep my promise.
妳贏了，那我將信守承諾
DO NOT ENTER STOP - DANGER
（危險，禁止穿越）
Kamiki! What are you doing?
神木，你在做什麼？
I told you.
我說過了
I dedicate my heart, body, and soul to you.
我將把身體和靈魂都獻給妳
Wait!
等等
Betting your life was just a joke!
讓你賭上性命只是個玩笑
I never joke around.
我從不開玩笑
Wait! Don't go any further!
等等，別再往前走了
Kamiki, stop this at once.
神木，快停下來
Kamiki!
神木
Okay, okay!
好吧，行
Okay! I'll lower the rent!
我明白了，我會降租
Please don't do it!
請別那樣
You can have all of my properties!
你可以負責我的所有房產
Thank you, Mrs. Kamogawa.
非常感謝，鴨川女士
You've helped me reach first place again this month.
妳幫我坐上了這個月的業務冠軍寶座
When my husband passed five years ago,
五年前，我丈夫去世時
he passed all his assets on to my son.
所有資產都留給了我兒子
He used that money to build the property.
他用那筆錢修建了那棟公寓
Said he wanted to pass it on to his own children.
說是以後想留給他自己的孩子
I've been holding my tongue,
我一直都沒有說話
but something seems off about him lately.
但他最近好像有些不對勁
But no matter how much I ask,
但是無論我怎麼問他
he just says everything's fine.
他只說沒事
I don't know what to do.
我不知道該如何是好
-I wanted to ask you-- -Mom.
-上次本來想問月下小姐… -媽
I'm heading out.
我出門了
MASANORI MATSUI MRS. MATSUI'S SON
（松井正則，惠美之子）
Hello.
你好
IMPORTANT REAL ESTATE DOCUMENTS MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（重要房產文件，密涅瓦不動產）
Masanori.
正則先生
Are you in a sublease contract with Minerva Real Estate?
你是不是跟密涅瓦不動產 簽訂了轉租合約？
I knew it.
果然如此
In that case, I can help you.
這樣的話，我可以幫你
-Masanori. Let's listen to what she has-- -Stop it, Mom.
-正則，月下小姐說… -別說了，媽
This has nothing to do with you. Leave! How can we trust a realtor?
與妳無關，出去 我們要怎麼相信一個房產仲介？
-We're not all like Minerva. -Get out of here!
-我們跟密涅瓦不一樣 -出去
-If you would just listen to me-- -Go! Leave!
-請聽我說… -給我走
-Masanori. -Leave!
-正則 -出去
REQUEST TO REDUCE RENT
（要求降租）
Why would you enter into a subleasing contract with Minerva?
你為何跟密涅瓦簽訂轉租合約？
SHINJI HAYAMA - OUR LANDLORD &amp; SAVIOR &amp; SUBLESSOR
（葉山進司，轉租人，大地主）
I wanted to help Ms. Hanasawa out.
我本來是想幫花澤
But then, out of the blue,
但是後來
some Kamiki guy is suddenly handling things.
突然冒出來一個叫神木的人 開始負責一切
Mr. Hayama, your contract says if you want to cancel
葉山先生，你的合約上寫著 如果想取消合約
you'll have to pay a huge penalty.
你必須支付鉅額違約金
Usually it'd only be three to six months' rent,
通常只需要三到六個月的房租
but here, it's 18 months' rent.
但這裡寫著18個月
18 months?
18個月？
This contract is difficult to terminate…
這種情況下，你身為轉租人…
HAYAMA - SUBLESSOR MINERVA - SUBLESSEE
（葉山-轉租人，密涅瓦-承租人）
…no matter how poorly you, the sublessor, are treated.
…無論條件多麼苛刻 都很難解除這份合約
PROTECTED UNDER THE ACT ON LAND AND BUILDING LEASES
（受《土地及建築物租賃法》保護）
You mean I'm stuck?
妳是說我被套牢了？
Can that happen?
可以這樣嗎？
It can.
可以
The Act offers protection for tenants,
法案的保護對象是承租人
but not for the property owners.
而非屋主
That gets distorted in a subleasing context.
在轉租的情況下 這項規定會被曲解和利用
So the Act's full of loopholes?
所以這法案其實充滿了漏洞？
Well, this is quite the pickle.
這下可麻煩了
NEW MESSAGE
（新訊息）
What's this?
什麼事？
Hey, this…
這個…
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
Never mind.
沒事
I just remembered I have plans.
我剛想起來還有事
-What? -I'm leaving.
-什麼？ -我先走了
-See you. -What?
-再見 -什麼？
-Wait, Mr. Hayama! -Mr. Hayama.
-等等，葉山先生 -葉山先生
Mr. Hayama, Mrs. Matsui's son,
葉山先生、松井女士的兒子
everyone's having issues with their sublease contracts with Minerva.
所有跟密涅瓦簽訂了轉租合約的人 都遇到了麻煩
The new subleasing laws that came into effect in 2020
2020年新通過的轉租法規定
say that the risks need to be disclosed, right?
必須提前告知風險，對嗎？
But we believe Mr. Kamiki has not been doing that.
但神木肯定沒那麼做
He never used to be this way.
他以前不是這樣的
He was a softy,
過去的他心地善良
and not good with words.
不善言辭
He barely made his quotas,
很難達到自己的業績目標
and he didn't seem at all the salesman type.
甚至看起來一點也不像個業務員
DADDY - ME - MOMMY
（爸爸、我、媽媽）
-I'm home. -Welcome back.
-我回來了 -歡迎回家
Shota, Daddy's home.
翔太，爸爸回來了
What happened to you?
你怎麼回事？
He fell during the race at preschool
他在幼稚園賽跑時摔倒了
and so he came in last.
所以跑了最後一名
Sports day is next week, right?
運動會是下週吧？
You'll just have to come in first then.
那你到時候跑第一就好
I can't.
我不可能跑第一
Of course you can.
當然可以
You can win anything if you put your mind to it.
只要用心去做，就一定能成功
Then maybe Daddy could lead by example.
那麼，也許爸爸能當個榜樣
All right then.
我知道了
Daddy will also come in first at his company this month.
爸爸這個月在公司也會拿到第一名
Let's be winners together.
翔太和爸爸一起當冠軍吧
With you?
跟爸爸一起？
Right.
對
I promise.
打鉤鉤
Pinkie swear, pinkie swear
打鉤鉤發誓
Cross my heart and hope to die Stick a needle in my eye
保證絕對不變，否則死蹺蹺
I promise
誰變就是小壞蛋
By the way, Shota.
對了，翔太
I want to show you something.
我有東西給你看
You ready?
準備好了嗎？
What sort of dance is this?
這是什麼舞步？
Tap dance.
踢踏舞
You said you wanted to learn. Right, Shota?
翔太說過想學，對吧？
No, Daddy!
才沒有
He said hip hop dance.
他說的是嘻哈舞
What?
什麼？
And I've been going to dance classes every week so I could teach you.
我最近每週都上舞蹈課，就為了教你
Silly Daddy.
爸爸笨笨
Daddy, do it again.
爸爸，再跳一次
I like it!
我喜歡
You do?
真的嗎？
All right. Watch closely now.
好，這次看仔細
But then…
但是後來…
there was the accident
出了那場事故
and he was never the same again.
他從此性情大變
On the day of his son's sports day…
就在他兒子運動會當天…
SHOTA FIGHT - DADDY FIGHT
（翔太加油，爸爸加油）
Mommy's fried chicken is the best!
媽媽做的炸雞最棒了
Yum. It's good.
真好吃
Shota.
翔太
We'll come in first place.
我們絕對會成為第一名
Yeah.
好的
I'll be there to see the foot race.
我會去現場看你賽跑
See you then.
到時候見
See you.
我走了
Bye, Daddy.
爸爸再見
Slow down, stay close to Mommy.
慢慢走，待在媽媽身邊
-You ran. -Yeah.
-你跑了 -對
Let's go.
走吧
He wasn't able to fulfill his promise.
可惜，他無法兌現自己的承諾
Poor thing. To be so young too…
真可憐，這麼小就…
Looks like a mother and her son.
好像是母子倆
They died instantly?
當場死亡嗎？
DADDY
（爸爸）
SHOTA FIGHT
（翔太加油）
Stop, you can't come through.
慢著，你不能過去
What are you doing? Step back!
你要幹什麼？請退後
Shota?
翔太？
Shota…
翔太…
Kaori?
香織
Shota!
翔太
Oh, dear…
這真是…
I went to visit him at home…
我去他家探望過…
MEMORIAL TABLET OCTOBER 17, 2009
（靈位 2009年10月17日）
Daddy's gonna prove it.
爸爸一定會證明
He'll prove you can come in first if you put your mind to it.
只要用心去做，就一定能拿第一
No, you can't.
你根本證明不了
Daddy's gonna come in first at work.
爸爸一定在工作中拿第一
No, I'm not lying.
我沒騙人，孩子的媽
Have faith in me.
請相信我
Shota.
翔太
Daddy's definitely gonna come in first.
爸爸一定會成為第一名
Then that month, he really did it.
那個月，他真的做到了
He was the top man in sales.
他成了業務冠軍
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
（辭呈）
And…
後來
he continued to be number one for the next nine years…
他連續九年穩坐著業務冠軍寶座
until Nagase beat him.
直到永瀨打敗了他
What do you think, Shota?
如何，翔太？
Daddy's gotten good, hasn't he?
爸爸跳得很棒吧？
Yeah. You're great!
嗯，爸爸真厲害
You know, when you and Mommy first went away,
知道嗎？翔太和媽媽剛走的時候
Daddy couldn't stop crying.
爸爸哭到不能自已
But I'll bet you and Mommy
但我知道，你和媽媽
don't like Daddy being a crybaby.
不希望爸爸當個愛哭鬼
Yeah.
對
Shota.
翔太
Your Daddy
爸爸
is gonna come in first this month, and next month,
這個月、下個月
and the next month and the next.
每個月都會當第一
You'll see.
你等著瞧吧
Daddy's not gonna let anyone ever beat him.
爸爸絕對不會被任何人打敗
Okay.
好的
Shall we dance?
我們跳舞吧？
Yeah.
好
You're good.
你跳得很好
We'll come in first place.
我們絕對會成為第一名
I promise.
我跟你打鉤鉤
Want to go for a bath?
永瀨，要不要去洗澡？
What?
什麼？
A bath.
洗澡
A bath?
洗澡？
I'm not really feeling it today.
我今天沒什麼心情
All the more reason to go.
那就更應該去了
Come on.
走吧？
Want to get ice cream after our bath?
洗完要不要吃個冰淇淋？
Sounds good.
好啊
What flavor will you get?
你要吃什麼口味的？
I'm gonna get lemon.
我要檸檬口味的
Green tea and red beans.
我要綠茶紅豆
You old man.
真老派
TOSAKA REAL ESTATE NO.1 IN THE AREA
（登坂不動產，本區第一）
What's wrong, Mr. Ishida?
石田先生，你怎麼來了？
You know a guy called Kamiki, yeah?
你認識一個叫神木的人吧？
He's a former colleague of mine.
他以前是我的同事
It's because of him
就因為他
that the landlords around town are at their wit's end.
這裡的房東們都一籌莫展
Can you help them?
你能幫他們嗎？
I'd love to help them,
我也想幫忙
but we're up against the Act on Land and Building Leases here.
但畢竟有《土地及建築物租賃法》
There's nothing I can do.
我也無能為力
You could just rip it up.
那種東西，撕了就行
This isn't something that can be just ripped up.
那可不是隨便就能撕毀的東西
Many laws have been wrong in the past.
過去有許多法案出了錯
They were ripped up and written anew.
於是被撕毀，重新擬定
Made the world a better place.
讓這世界變得更加美好
Anything's possible.
一切皆有可能
-Mr. Nagase. -Yes?
-永瀨先生 -什麼事？
You're the only one who can do it.
只有你能做到
I'm the only one?
只有我嗎？
Peace.
和平
Everyone here is having difficulties with a subleasing contract with Minerva.
在座的各位都因為跟密涅瓦不動產 簽訂轉租合約而遇到了麻煩
PROPERTY OWNERS CURRENTLY IN SUBLEASING CONTRACT WITH MINERVA
（目前與密涅瓦 簽訂了轉租合約的房東）
We'd like to help you out.
我們想幫助各位
Didn't I already tell you not to bother with this?
我不是已經叫你們別管這件事了嗎？
The fact that you're all here after we sent the word out
可是我們放出消息後，各位都來了
means you all agree something needs to be done about this.
這表示各位都認為必須採取行動
-Let's go, Mom. -Masanori?
-媽，我們走 -正則？
We haven't finished here.
我們還沒說完
There's nothing to discuss!
沒什麼好說的
Let's go.
我們走
You know that's not true--
你明知並非如此
You good-for-nothing, profligate son of Mrs. Matsui!
松井女士的兒子 你真是個一無是處的敗家子…
Sir.
先生
GOOD-FOR-NOTHING PROFLIGATE SON
（一無是處的敗家子先生）
Minerva tempted you with the investment of a lifetime,
密涅瓦不動產誘導你 進行“千載難逢”的投資
so you took your late father's inheritance
所以你就用已故父親的遺產
and used it to construct a 200-million-yen property.
修建了價值兩億元的公寓
This guy's never invested in real estate in his life,
這傢伙一輩子都沒投資過房地產
and now he's getting ripped off and up to his neck in debt.
現在被人騙，還欠了一屁股債
How'd you know that?
你怎麼會知道這些？
I did some digging.
我做了些調查
Is it true, Masanori?
正則，是真的嗎？
And Mr. Yamada, don't think you're off the hook.
山田先生，別以為你能置身事外
You were also so tempted by the profits promised to you
你也被密涅瓦承諾的利潤所誘
that you secretly ate into you and your wife's savings,
所以偷偷動用了你和太太的存款
bought an investment property, and subleased it to Minerva.
買了一處投資用的房子 還轉租給了密涅瓦
PURCHASED AN INVESTMENT PROPERTY WITHOUT TELLING HIS WIFE
（瞞著太太投資房產）
Obviously Minerva should not have lured you in with honeyed words,
當然，密涅瓦不該 用花言巧語哄騙你們
but you were all simply too eager to accept them at face value.
可是各位 你們連那種話都信，真的太天真了
Far too eager!
太天真了
You're as eager as one partner expecting a kiss on the first date.
你們就像 第一次約會就想得到熱吻的伴侶
And as for the cherry on top, that would be Mr. Hayama.
要說個中翹楚，就非葉山先生莫屬了
Me?
我？
During our meeting, you got a text message which completely changed your mood after.
咱們之前面談時 你收到一則簡訊之後就態度大變
Isn't this what you were looking at?
你收到的是這個嗎？
WE GOT TO RIDE ON MR. HAYAMA'S YACHT
（乘坐葉山大人的遊艇出海啦）
No!
不會吧
You bought a yacht for the tax benefits, yes?
你為了享受稅收優惠 而買了艘遊艇吧？
It's meant to be a fringe benefit for employees,
這本該是員工的附加福利
but no one ever gets to go on it
但根本沒人享受過
because you're always out there
因為你總是
paying gorgeous women to join you on boat raves, aren't you?
花錢請美女 跟你一起出海狂歡，不是嗎？
Do you realize that if they determine your tax write off as disingenuous,
你知道嗎？ 如果政府認定你虛報以申請減免
it could be considered as tax evasion, you--
可能構成逃漏稅，你這個…
bald old creep.
老禿驢
TAX EVADER - OLD CREEP
（逃稅的老禿驢）
How did you even get this picture?
你怎麼會有這張照片？
One of these lovely ladies uploaded it to social media.
照片上的一位女士 把它上傳到了社交媒體
Oh, my God!
不會吧
You really need to up your crisis management skills.
你真得提升一下處理危機的能力
I'll bet Kamiki sent you a similar photo
我敢打賭，我們上次面談時
during that meeting that we had, didn't he?
密涅瓦不動產的神木 一定是傳類似的照片給你吧？
Did Mr. Kamiki tell you that the Supreme Court
各位威脅要起訴時，神木是不是說
had already handed down rulings when you threatened to sue?
針對類似情況 最高法院此前已經有過判例？
He did say that.
沒錯
The Supreme Court has already made rulings on this.
最高法院此前已經有過判例
He said sublessees are protected under the Act on Land and Building Leases.
他說承租人受到 《土地及建築物租賃法》的保護
-He said that to me too. -Minerva is just saying that to scare you.
-他也是這麼跟我說的 -密涅瓦只是用這種話來嚇唬各位
You shouldn't let such a nasty company keep you up at night.
大家不該任由這種卑劣的公司 讓自己寢食難安
But there's nothing we can do if they've got the law on their side.
但是我們無能為力啊 畢竟法律都站在他們那邊
No, we must not give up.
不，我們不能放棄
Nothing will ever change if we don't speak up now.
如果現在不出聲，就不會有任何改變
Corporate entities do not suffer under this Act on Land and Building Leases.
受《土地及建築物租賃法》 影響最大的並非大企業
It is you, small mom-and-pop investors, who are suffering.
而是各位這樣的小型投資人
You could bury your heads in the sand,
大家可以自欺欺人，對問題視而不見
but then what will happen to all those people needing to rent?
但那些需要租屋的人怎麼辦？
Let's speak up for the sake of our community.
我們一起為了社區而發聲吧
We're going to sue Minerva Real Estate together.
我們要集體對密涅瓦不動產提告
Sue?
提告？
Yes.
對
We'll go to trial.
我們要出庭
A trial?
出庭？
Go to trial?
鬧上法庭？
All right.
我明白了
Let's sue!
那就提告吧
That photo doesn't scare me!
那照片嚇不倒我
I'm in.
我加入
I'll join too.
我也加入
Masanori.
正則
Your father was this town's mayor.
你父親曾是這個鎮的鎮長
He would have spoken up for the people in his community.
他若還在世 一定也會為自己社區的人們發聲
I'll do it!
我加入
Come on, everyone.
來吧，各位
We can do this.
我們一定能成功
NOTICE OF TERMINATION OF CONTRACT
（合約解除通知書）
SUBLEASE CONTRACT
（轉租合約）
NOTICE OF TERMINATION OF SUBLEASE CONTRACT - APPLICANTS
（轉租合約解除通知書，申請者）
YUKIO IZUTSU - LAWYER
（井筒由紀夫，律師）
These are all the people with whom you have a sublease contract
這些都是跟你們密涅瓦 簽訂了轉租合約的人
who would like to terminate their oppressive contracts.
他們想解除苛刻的合約
Do you even know what you're doing?
你們知道自己在幹什麼嗎？
The contract may not stipulate it,
合約中可能沒有明確規定
but an owner must have justifiable grounds to terminate from their side.
但房東必須提供正當理由 才能解除合約
They are all aware.
他們都很清楚
They would still like to terminate.
但他們仍想解除
If you refuse, we'll file a class-action lawsuit.
如果你們拒絕，我們會提出集體訴訟
A class-action lawsuit?
集體訴訟？
Go ahead. Sue.
去啊，儘管告
The Supreme Court has already passed judgments.
最高法院此前已經有過判例
Yes, they have.
對，確實有過
"They've made rulings. They've handed down judgments."
“他們此前已經有過判例 已經做出過判決”
You parrot that like it's the only thing you know how to say.
你們這些鸚鵡就只會這麼說
I think it's time to expand your vocabulary!
我覺得你們真該擴展一下詞彙量了
Higashino. Escort them out.
東野，送他們出去
Okay.
是
We're not leaving.
我們不走
We can no longer ignore
我們不能再任由你們
what you're doing to this community.
繼續對這個社區為所欲為
The community?
這個社區？
When you strangle the landlords,
你們把房東逼上絕路
you inevitably strangle their tenants and everyone else in the community.
就會不可避免地把他們的房客 和社區裡的其他人也逼上絕路
You'll decrease the quality of life, and people will leave.
這裡的生活品質會下降、人們會搬離
Is that what you want, Kamiki?
神木，這是你想看到的結果嗎？
You and your family used to live around here too, right?
你和你的家人也曾在這裡生活過吧？
If you still insist on doing this, then let's contest it in court.
如果你堅持這麼做 那我們就到法庭上一決高下吧
But the courts like to air out all the dirty laundry.
但法庭的背景調查 很可能挖出一切不堪的過往
It's likely that all the past wrongdoings of your president
你們社長過去的一切不法行為
will also come out to see the light of day.
都可能浮出水面
Are you really doing this?
你真要這麼做嗎？
I am.
是的
Remember, I cannot tell a lie.
畢竟，我無法說謊
There's the final boss.
幕後首腦來了
What was that?
妳說什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼
I heard everything.
我都聽到了
Mr. Nagase.
永瀨先生
You really are fascinating, you know that?
你還是那麼瀟灑迷人啊
Do as you please.
請便
Let's go.
我們走
Okay.
好
You have a poor endgame, Nagase.
出手還是不夠狠啊，永瀨
Remember what I told you?
記得我是怎麼教你的嗎？
You should beat down your competition by any means necessary.
你該不擇手段地擊敗競爭對手
That's why you'll never come in first.
難怪你永遠當不了第一
I don't care about coming in first anymore.
我已經不在乎是否能當第一了
I've found something even more important than that.
我找到了更重要的事
And what is that?
是什麼？
Please, do tell.
說來聽聽
Come up with your own.
你自己好好想想吧
Looks like everyone got out of their contract with Minerva
看來大家都成功擺脫了密涅瓦的合約
without needing to pay any hefty penalties.
並且不用支付鉅額違約金
Wow, Mr. Nagase.
永瀨先生
-You really saved me. -No worries.
-你真是救了我一命 -言重了
Wanna come for a cruise on my yacht as thanks?
要不要坐我的遊艇遊覽一番？ 算是我的謝禮
I'm sure the ladies will flock to us when they hear you're coming.
女孩們要是聽說你會來 一定會蜂擁而至
No, Mr. Hayama. I'm fine.
不了，葉山先生，謝謝
You should take your family or your employees instead.
你應該帶家人或員工出海
I actually really want to go!
其實我很想去
I wanna ride your yacht!
我想駕駛你的遊艇
I wanna ride with all those lovely ladies!
想跟所有可愛的女孩們一起出海
Please let me come.
請帶我去吧
Excuse me. That was weird.
抱歉，失禮了
You really are an overly honest man.
真是個誠實過頭的笨蛋呢
I'm sorry.
抱歉
That's why I trust you.
就是因為這樣，我才信任你
Thank you.
謝謝
-I look forward to working with you. -Yes, thank you.
-我很期待跟你合作 -好的，謝謝
Tsukishita told me.
月下都告訴我了
About your son and your wife.
關於你妻兒的遭遇
I have a son too.
我自己也有個兒子
So I can understand how much it must hurt.
所以我明白你有多痛苦
But it's still no excuse to go as far as you did.
但那仍不能成為 你迄今為止所作所為的藉口
Don't you think it's time to stop obsessing over being number one?
你不覺得是時候住手了嗎？ 別再執著於當第一了
No.
不
I won't stop.
我不會住手
Ever since my wife and my son died,
自從我妻兒離去
I've only ever not been first once.
我只有一次沒得到第一名
That's when
就是那次
they disappeared.
他們就消失了
Disappeared?
消失？
When I fell to second place,
我落到第二名時
Kaori and Shota disappeared.
香織和翔太就不出現了
But as soon as I came in first again…
但我一旦重回第一
they came back to me.
他們就會回到我身邊
Look.
妳看
They're over there.
他們就在那裡
I never
我再也…
want to lose you two again.
不想失去你們了
Did Miss Enomoto make that for you?
這是榎本小姐為你準備的嗎？
It's her turn today, so she made it for me.
今天輪到她做飯，所以她做了這些
-It looks good. -Hi, everyone.
-看起來很好吃 -我來了
Tokage? Why are you so late to work?
十影？今天怎麼這麼晚？
CRYPTO REAL TIME CHART
（加密貨幣即時走勢圖）
Crypto's crashed and I've lost it all.
加密貨幣崩盤，我全輸光了
CRYPTO (VIRTUAL CURRENCY)
（加密貨幣，虛擬貨幣）
I sold everything, the suit and the watch, but it wasn't enough…
我把西裝和鞋子都賣了還是不夠
I told you to just focus on your job.
我早說了你該專心工作
So, Mr. Nagase, what are you going to do?
話說回來，永瀨前輩打算怎麼做？
About what?
什麼怎麼做？
About Miss Enomoto.
跟榎本小姐
You can't just keep living together, can you?
你們總不能一直同居吧？
I guess not.
應該不行
I guess I do like being with her.
我好像確實喜歡跟她在一起
It's like I don't have to wear a mask around her,
就感覺在她身邊 我不用戴著面具生活
and I can just be myself.
可以安心做自己
I've never felt this way before…
我以前從沒有過這種感覺
Does that mean…
難道說…
I'm thinking it's about time I tell her.
我覺得是時候告訴她了
Wow, really?
真的嗎？
Oh, my goodness, Mr. Nagase. I'm so happy for you!
天啊，永瀨前輩，我真替你們開心
Come on, stop it.
拜託，別這樣
What?
什麼？
MITSUTOMO BANK
（光友銀行）
You want me to move?
你想把我調去別的地方？
To New York?
去紐約？
CRYPTO REAL TIME CHART
（加密貨幣即時走勢圖）
It went down again.
又跌了
Tokage.
十影
Here we go.
推起來
PERMISSION GRANTED TO CONVERT AGRICULTURAL LAND
（獲准更改農業用地）
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
This is six years in the making.
登坂不動產準備了整整六年
I'm thinking any setbacks would be fatal.
我認為任何阻礙都足以致命
What happens to the project if Mr. Sayama cancels his contract?
如果狹山先生取消合約 對專案會有什麼影響？
Be a father who holds his head high.
做一個抬頭挺胸的父親
She's a valued partner of mine.
她是我珍貴的伴侶
What he said.
沒錯
THE HONEST REALTOR 2 EP 9 - A MAN NAMED KAMIKI
第9集：神木其人